BRIAN SHANKEN

4252 Shadow Garden Drive • Hahira, GA 31602 • (912) 532-1978 • bcshanken@gmail.com Portfolio: https://bcshanken.github.io/Portfolio/

CAREER PROFILE

Full stack web developer with 7 years' experience in database management, process optimization, and landing page design with a focus on lead generation within medium sized companies. Experienced in working with back end data for both internal and external users, designing and developing web-based lead generation processes, and building employee databases which optimize procedures. Currently on track to graduate from Georgia Tech with certification as a full stack web developer in February 2021.

Core competencies within the field of web development include both front end and back end skills such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, jQuery, express.js, MySQL, Command Line, Git, Bootstrap, test-driven development, Progressive Web Apps, Agile Methodology, React.js, and MongoDB. Outside of web development, I also have proficiency with the CRM platforms, Pardot and Salesforce; CSMs such as Insight and Mojo; operations management; data processing; reporting and presentations in Microsoft Suite, specializing in Microsoft Excel; and lead process development. Worked in multiple industries helping a variety of companies to pair technology with data driven decisions to achieve success.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- Introduced landing pages to the marketing process to generate additional prospects and sales-ready leads. Through this method, our prospect database grew from 9k to 16k over the course of two years by means of prospect engagement, SEO development, and content-driven webpages with prospect generating CTAs.
- Developed database for a call center to record and present performance on over one thousand customer service agents and their management teams. This system saved over 3,520 working hours over four years by reducing the time spent each week by 85%, from over 20 hours to 3 hours each week, while providing more detail and offering the capability of weekly custom reporting.
- Built an application that uses multisource API data to link patterns between the number of COVID-19 cases and NASDAQ stock values to provide users with a greater insight into potential investments and financial decisions.

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Atlanta, GA, 2021

Certification: Full Stack Web Development

VALDOSTA STATE UNIVERSITY, Valdosta, GA, 2013

B.S., Physics, minor in Mathematics and Astronomy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CLEAVER-BROOKS, INC. Thomasville, GA

2017-2020

Cleaver-Brooks is an international manufacturing company best known for their line of Firetube Boilers and being an industry leader in technology and expertise.

Marketing Operations Manager, 2018-2020

In this role, I was responsible for the technical side of marketing. I provided the background assistance to ensure the marketing department functioned smoothly and successfully.

- Developed customer engagement programs designed to build interests based on customer interactions
- Designed and built HTML-based marketing emails that focused on providing clear CTAs and metrics to the marketing department
- Created HTML mobile first landing page designs for advertising, events, and document gates

BRIAN SHANKEN

4252 Shadow Garden Drive • Hahira, GA 31602 • (912) 532-1978 • bcshanken@gmail.com Portfolio: https://bcshanken.github.io/Portfolio/

- Maintained and developed a database of over 16k prospects
- Connected marketing operations to external sales team through CRMs by creating the prospect-to-lead-to-opportunity pipeline
- Modified corporate websites based on data-driven decisions

Market Analyst, 2017-2018

As a market analyst I was responsible for providing the data insights used for evaluating and moving forward with both marketing initiatives and business plans.

- Monitored SEO and Google AdWords
- Generated reports for marketing advertisements, email campaigns, and engagement programs
- Aggregated sales performance for all divisions in the corporation to be presented to the executive board
- Prepared external data paired with internal data in order to show company projections
- · Analyzed website performance for five different corporate websites and provided advisable actions to take

DATA SOFTWARE SERVICES, Valdosta, GA

2013-2017

Data Software Services is a solution-driven company that provides data insight to car dealerships around the country. The company performs and follows up with surveys for the dealerships in order to improve customer experience.

Business Analyst

I built solutions for management with no technical training to be able to understand and use amassed data.

- Utilized a SQL database for reporting to both internal and external customers
- Analyzed work performance of Customer Service Representatives of the call center
- Performed statistical trend analyses for maximizing performance efficiency
- Created cost analyses of company promotions
- Presented technical findings and business insights to senior management for use in business decisions making
- Analyzed and modified admin and managerial processes to save time and improve accuracy
- Entered high volumes of data and created interactive statistical presentations for managers
- Developed and maintained accurate time records to submit for payroll

VALDOSTA STATE UNIVERSITY, STUDENT SUCCESS CENTER, Valdosta, GA 2009-2013

The student success center is an additional instructional opportunity available for all VSU students which provides free personal tutoring and supplies classrooms with supplemental instructors.

Supplemental Instructor, 2011-2013

- Assisted the professors with presenting the course material for a trigonometry and an astronomy class
- Performed as a second resource to students through one-on-one office appointments and review sessions for large quantities of students of various learning levels

Peer Tutor, 2009-2013

- Lead over 3,000 private and group tutoring sessions in over 20 mathematics and physics courses
- Helped students prepare for standardized tests, from Air Force officer exams to graduate school entrance exams

VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES

INTERNATIONAL STUDENT VOLUNTEERS, San Cristobal Norte, Costa Rica, 2010

Volunteer – Participated in a summer volunteer program in Costa Rica, helping lay the foundations for a water tank and pave roads in a developing community while learning Spanish and Costa Rican culture and customs.